# M TABARIK ASIF

## ETHICAL HACKER, PENETRATION TESTER, BUG HUNTER, CS GRADUATE



**)** (+92) 320-8098749

in LinkedIn Profile

mtabarikasif@gmail.com

mtabarikasif

# PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Organized Departmental Activities (Conferences and Project Exhibitions), Conducted Cyber security workshops in CS department to spread awareness and teach ethical hacking techniques based on previously discovered vulnerabilities.

President Society of Computer Technology (2023-2024)

PROFILE

Experienced Cybersecurity professional, Ethical Hacker and Bug Bounty Hunter with over 3 years of real-world

experience, Specializes in offensive and defensive

security. Proficient in Web/API hacking, automation, Cloud Security, OWASP top 10, Cyber Security tools

and Scripting. Curious Learner, Tech Enthusiast,

President Society of Computer Technology.

- IBM Cyber Security Analyst (2024)
- Google Cybersecurity Professional Certificate (2023)
- CompTIA Security+ (Udemy) (2024)
- LinkedIn Learning Become an Ethical Hacker (2022)
- Other Relevant Security Certifications (TCM Sec, Udemy)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Bug Hunting** Bugcrowd, Hackerone, Private | Remote | 2021 - Present Proficiently identified and resolved critical vulnerabilities across Bugcrowd, HackerOne, and private platforms, demonstrating proficiency in security assessments. Fostered efficient collaborations and swift issue resolution through professional communication standards.

- Successfully discovered and reported high-impact bugs, encompassing SQLI, XSS, **IDOR, Broken Authentication,** and Security Misconfigurations.
- Executed an Authentication Bypass vulnerability (P1) on Jenkins, leading to the resolution of a critical bug for a globally recognized, multi-billion-dollar soft drinks company.
- Uncovered exposed database backups and live data on Telefonica Germany's assets and Tecno respectively, highlighting security gaps and contributing to enhanced data protection measures.
- Identified and reported an RXSS vulnerability on Tecno, resulting in the attainment of Hall of Fame recognition.

**Virtual Internships and Job Simulations** Forage | 2023,2024

Successfully Completed Virtual internships and Job simulations, for Mastercard, ANZ Australia, JPMorgan Chase & Co and Clifford Chance. Deepening expertise in business awareness, legal assessment, network traffic analysis, anti-phishing tactics, standards compliance impact analysis, and social engineering concepts.

**Projects** Cybersecurity Projects | 2020 – Present

Projects developed exclusively for the field of Cybersecurity, spanning from 2020 to the present.

- Final Year Project: Developed a web vulnerability scanner as FYP.
- Python Keylogger: A Python keylogger with screenshot capabilities Emphasized ethical user for educational purposes and testing scenarios.
- Automation Projects: Developed diverse automation projects, including automated recon, versatile bash scripts, efficient in bug bounty.
- AWS WAF Deployment: Designed and implemented AWS WAF, acquiring expertise in ACLs, rules, bot control, integrations, IP sets and rule groups for effective security.
- **Semester Projects:** Executed multiple <u>semester projects</u> across diverse language and technologies, exploring new skill in NLP-based chatbots, LLMs Hacking, Networking tools and various other projects.

## EDUCATION

# // Bachelor of CS

Hazara University (2024)

#### SKILLS

#### // Technical Skills

**BASH Scripting** Reconnaissance Web/API Hacking OWASP Top 10 Google Dorking **CVSS** 

## // Tools

**Burp Suite SQLMap** Metasploit Nmap Nessus

AWARDS

# **Techno Hall of Fame**

Safe Keeper

# **Submission Shogun**

Bugcrowd - 2023

## **Private Hall of Fame**

Achieved HOF on private bug bounty **Programs** 

### **Elite Member**

Township local Welfare - 2023

# **SCT Performance Award**

**CS Society Award**